A Guide to the Christopher C. Kraft Papers, 1941-1982
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Christopher C. Kraft Papers, 1941-1998 (Bulk, 1941-1982)
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1985-001
28 cu. ft. 27 boxes; 5 folders
The collection consists of approximately 28 cu. ft. of manuscripts, particularly NACA and NASA reports and documents, meeting notes and agendas, and research materials. A later donation contains the manuscript for 2001 Kraft's autobiography.
Kraft, Christopher C.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The majority of the collection was given to Newman Library in November 1985 and formally donated in April 1986. Additional materials were donated to Special Collections in January 2003.
Biographical Note
Christopher Columbus Kraft, Jr. was born on February 28, 1924, in Phoebus, Virginia. He received his BS degree in aeronautical engineering from Virginia Polytechnic Institute (Virginia Tech) in December 1944.
Kraft joined the Langley Aeronautical Laboratory of the National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics (NACA) in 1945 as a flight engineer. In October 1958, he was selected as one of the original members of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) Space Task Group, which had been established to manage Project Mercury, the nation's first project to put a man in space. In the early phases of Project Mercury, Kraft was a prime contributor to the development of many of the basic mission and flight control techniques used in manned space flight. He personally served as Flight Director for all the Mercury missions and many of the Gemini missions. During the latter phase of Project Mercury, he directed the design and implementation of the Mission Control Center at the Johnson Space Center (originally the Manned Spacecraft Center) in Houston, from which all of NASA's manned space flights have been conducted. Kraft was named deputy director of the Manned Spacecraft Center in 1970, and later director in 1972. He retired from NASA in 1982 and and subsequently served as a consultant for various corporations. In 2001, Kraft's autobiography, Flight: My Life in Mission Control was published.
Kraft has been the recipient of a number of awards and honors, including three honorary doctorates (Indiana Institute of Technology, 1966; St. Louis University, 1967; and Villanova University, 1979); the NASA Outstanding Leadership Medal, 1963; the NASA Distinguished Service Medal, 1969; the American Astronautical Society's Space Flight Award, 1970; and the Ambassador of Exploration Award, 2006. In 2011, the Johnson Space Center renamed its Mission Control Center the Christopher C. Kraft Jr. Mission Control Center in his honor.
Recent News:
NASA Names Mission Control for Legendary Flight Director Christopher Kraft, April 14, 2011
Air & Space Magazine Interview, March 17, 2010
Johnson Space Center Oral History Project
Scope and Content
The collection consists of approximately 28 cu. ft. of manuscripts, particularly NACA and NASA reports and documents, meeting notes and agendas, and research materials. A later donation contains the manuscript for Kraft's autobiography.
From Kraft's early years at Langley Flight Research Division, the collection includes notes, calculations, and drawings for many projects (testing the stability and control of the X-1, P-47 Thunderbolt, and P-51 H Mustang airplanes, for example). It also includes calculations and draft reports on the gust-alleviation system designed by Kraft and then-division head, William Hewitt Phillips.
The collection contains heavily-annotated editions of "Mission Rules" for Project Mercury, extensive files of post-launch reports and astronaut debriefing transcripts from Kraft's early NASA years (1958-1970), as well as correspondence, notes, and memoranda. Materials from Kraft's later years at NASA (1970-1982) include professional notes, detailing meetings and telephone conversations, plus meeting agendas, memos, and other work documents.
Arrangement
For the most part, the collection in arranged in chronological order. Whenever the exact date is unknown, materials are filed at the end of the known month or year. Oversize drawings, sketches, blueprints, calculations, graphs, and charts were removed from the collection and are arranged in their original order in folders. Oversize newspaper clippings, for preservation purposes, are in a separate oversize folder.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Papers from several individuals with whom Kraft worked are available at Special Collections, including:
Ms1987-057, Melvin N. Gough Papers
Ms90-053, Robert R. Gilruth Papers
Ms2005-019, William Hewitt Phillips Papers
Descriptions of additional Archives of American Aerospace Exploration collections are available online at http://spec.lib.vt.edu/aerosp/.
Index Terms
Persons:
Kraft, Christopher C.
Corporate Names:
Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center.; Project Mercury (U.S.).
Subjects:
Archives of American Aerospace Exploration (AAAE); Langley Aeronautical Laboratory; Manned Spacecraft Center (U.S.); Project Apollo (U.S.); Project Gemini (U.S.); Science and Technology; United States. National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration; University Archives; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- 1941
  - Handbook of Mathematical Tables and Formulas, 1941 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - U.S. War Department Manual on Physiological Aspects of Flying, 1941 (Box-folder 1-2)
- 1942
  - U.S. War Department Publication on Strength of Aircraft Elements, 1942 (Box-folder 1-3)
- 1944
  - VPI Aeronautical Engineering Department: Lab Reports, 1944 (Box-folder 1-4)
- 1945
  - Course Notes: Appreciation and Prediction of Flying Qualities, 1945 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Notes on NACA Symbols, Definitions, and Airplane Axes, c. 1945 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - P47-D: Airspeed Calibrations, 1945 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - P47-D: Photographs, 1945 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - P47-D: Reports and Calculations, 1945 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - P47-D: Reports and Calculations, 1945 (Box-folder 1-10)
  - P47-D: Reports and Calculations, 1945 (Box-folder 1-11)
  - P51-H: Airspeed Calibrations, 1945 (Box-folder 1-12)
- 1946
  - P51-H: Photographs, 1946 (Box-folder 1-14)
  - P51-H: Memoranda, 1946 (Box-folder 1-13)
  - P51-H: Reports, 1946 (Box-folder 1-15)
  - P51-H: Reports, 1946 (Box-folder 1-16)
- 1947
  - Index of NACA Technical Publications: 1915-1947, 1947 (Box-folder 1-17)
  - Research Memorandum on the Stability and Control of the P51-H, 1947 (Box-folder 1-18)
  - X-51 Auto Pilot: Photographs, c. 1947 (Box-folder 1-19)
  - Miscellaneous Papers on Roll Stability, 1947-1958 (Box-folder 1-20)
  - Langley Golf League Records, 1947-1958 (Box-folder 1-21)
  - X-51 Drop Model: Notes, 1947 (Box-folder 1-22)
- 1948
  - Bench Set-Up Gust Alleviator: Drawings, 1948 (Box-folder 1-23)
  - Free-fall Test of Bell XS-1 Airplane: Report, 1948 (Box-folder 1-24)
  - NACA Public Relations Brochure: The Organization-Research Activities and Facilities of the NACA, 1948 (Box-folder 1-25)
  - NAVAER SR-119B: Specification for Flying Qualities of Piloted Airplanes, 1948 (Box-folder 1-26)
- 1949
  - Bench Set-Up Gust Alleviator: Data, 1949 (Box-folder 1-27)
  - Calculations of the Wave Drag at Supersonic Speeds of Non-Lifting Wings with Arbitrary Sweepback and Aspect Ratio, 1949 (Box-folder 1-28)
  - Canard Drop Model: Notes, 1949 (Box-folder 1-29)
  - Canard Drop Model: Report and Calculations, 1949 (Box-folder 1-30)
  - Canard Drop Model: Report on Free-fall Characteristics, c. 1949 (Box-folder 1-31)
  - Canard Drop Model: Talk for Transonic Conference, 1949 (Box-folder 1-32)
  - Canard Drop Model Report: Data, 1949 (Box-folder 1-33)
  - Canard Drop Model Report: Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box-folder 1-34)
  - Canard Drop Model Report: Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box-folder 1-35)
  - Canard Drop Model Report: Rough Draft, 1949 (Box-folder 1-36)
  - Canard Drop Model Report: Speech, 1949 (Box-folder 1-37)
  - Caricature of Christopher Kraft, c. 1949 (Box-folder 1-38)
  - FrD Drop Model NO.1: Photographs, c. 1949 (Box-folder 2-1)
  - FRD Drop Model No.3, 1949 (Box-folder 2-2)
  - REAC: Operation, Basic Concepts, Phillips Problem, c. 1949 (Box-folder 2-3)
  - Transparencies "For Kraft from Brown," c. 1949 (Box-folder 2-4)
  - Loads Committee: Work on F-80 Tail Loads during Gunnery Runs, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Notebook (disbound) Containing Reports on Flight Stability and Control, Flying Qualities, etc., 1949-1956 (Box-folder 2-6)
  - Notebook (disbound) containing Memos on Flight Stability and control, Flying Qualities, etc., 1949-1956 (Box-folder 2-7)
  - Notebook (disbound) containing Notes on Flight Stability and Control, Flying Qualities, etc., 1949-1956 (Box-folder 2-8)
  - NASA Safety Guide, c. 1949 (Box-folder 3-33)
- 1950
  - NACA Report: Drag and Longitudinal Stability and Control Characteristics of a Concord Model at Transonic Speeds, 1950 (Box-folder 2-9)
  - Proceedings, NACA Conference on "Some Problems of Aircraft Operation," 1950 (Box-folder 2-10)
  - Tables and Charts on Air Speed and Air Speed Indication, c. 1950 (Box-folder 2-11)
  - XF-91 Drag Calculations, 1950 (Box-folder 2-12)
- 1951
  - Technical Note 2416: Methods of Increasing the Smoothness of Flight Through Rough Air, 1951 (Box-folder 2-14)
  - Notes for Servo Course Lectures - IRD, 1951 (Box-folder 2-15)
  - Miscellaneous Clipped Articles on Automatic Flight Control, 1951 (Box-folder 2 16)
  - NACA Technical Notes: No. 2238, No. 2275, No. 2311, No.2415, 1951 (Box-folder 2-17)
  - NACA Technical Note 2415: Experimental Study of Angle of Attack Vane Mounted Ahead of the Nose of an Airplane for use as a sensing device for and Acceleration Alleviator, 1951 (Box-folder 2-13)
- 1952
  - SAE Controls Committee, 1952-1957 (Box-folder 3-20)
  - NACA Technical Notes:No. 1101, No.2675, No. 3313, 1952 (Box-folder 2-18)
  - Hirsch, Rene - Correspondence Regarding Gust Alleviation, 1952 (Box-folder 2-19)
  - Calculations for Nike and Sparrow Rockets, 1952 (Box-folder 2-20)
- 1953
  - NACA: Security Regulations, 1953 (Box-folder 2-21)
  - Analysis of a Vane Controlled Gust Alleviation System, 1953 (Box-folder 2-22)
  - NACA Technical Note: No 28599, No.3243, 1953 (Box-folder 2-23)
  - Miscellaneous Suppliers' Literature, 1953 (Box-folder 2-24)
  - Vortices: Speech for Department Meeting at Cleveland, 1953 (Box-folder 2-25)
- 1954
  - Talk at VPI on Gust Alleviation, 1954 (Box-folder 2-26)
  - Proceedings, NACA Conference on Some Problems of Aircraft Operation, 1954 (Box-folder 2-28)
  - Notes and Drafts of Speech of Gust Alleviation, 1954 (Box-folder 2-27)
  - Trailing Vortices: Notes for Presentation, 1954 (Box-folder 2-29)
  - Trailing Vortices: Report on Strength and Persistence, 1954 (Box-folder 2-30)
  - Trailing Vortices: Photographs, 1954 (Box-folder 2-31)
  - NACA Technical Note NO. 3317, 1954 (Box-folder 2-32)
- 1955
  - NACA Proceedings: Conference on Automatic Stability and Control of Aircraft, 1955 (Box-folder 2-33)
  - C-45 Speech for Conference on Automatic Control, 1955 (Box-folder 2-34)
  - Talk on Gust Alleviation System: Automatic Control of Gust Response, 1955 (Box-folder 3-35)
  - Talk of Gust Alleviation System for Patuxent Test Pilots, 1955 (Box-folder 2-36)
  - XB-51: Preliminary Calculations, 1955 (Box-folder 2-37)
  - Notes on Analysis of Vibration Absorber, 1955 (Box-folder 2-38)
- 1956
  - Cornell University Report: Mechanically Implemented Normal Acceleration Limiting System, June 1956 (Box-folder 3-1)
  - Memorandum: Airplane Motions and Vertical-Tail Loads when Passing Another Plane at Low Supersonic Speeds, October 1, 1956 (Box-folder 3-2)
  - Presentations: Piloting Problems Incurred on Ballistic Re-Entry, October-November, 1956 (Box-folder 3-3)
  - Douglas Aircraft Company Paper: Gust Alleviation, November 14, 1956 (Box-folder 3-4)
  - ARDC Regulation Regarding Development Testing of Guided Missiles, November 20, 1956 (Box-folder 3-5)
  - Forty Years of Aeronautical Research, 1956 (Box-folder 3-6)
  - NACATechnical Note No. 3635, No. 3702, 1956 (Box-folder 3-7)
  - Index of NACA Technical Publications, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 3-10)
- 1957
  - NACA Technical Note No. 3954, No. 4046, No. 4047, No. 4171, 1957 (Box-folder 3-8)
  - Speech for Loads Conference: Gust Alleviation, 1957 (Box-folder 3-11)
  - Range Recovery Materials, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 3-12)
  - Personnel Memos, 1957-1961 (Box-folder 3-13)
  - Miscellaneous Personnel Records, 1957-1961 (Box-folder 3-14)
- 1958
  - NACA Technical Note No. 4196, No. 4276, D-173, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 3-9)
  - Talk to Patuxent Test Pilots: F80-1 Navy Airplane, May 21, 1958 (Box-folder 3-15)
  - Air Force Ballistic Missile Division Memo: Flight Test Procedures, May 1958 (Box-folder 3-16)
  - Aeronatucs Committee of the SAE Technical Board, July 1958 (Box-folder 3-17)
  - RCA Report: Downrange Antiballistic Measurement Program, c. 1958 (Box-folder 3-18)
  - Pressure Switch Test Results, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 3-19)
  - SAE Controls Committee, 1958 (Box-folder 3-21)
  - C-45 Gust Alleviation Report, c. 1958 (Box-folder 4-18)
- 1959
  - Draft: NASA Modus Operandi on Atlantic Missile Range, January 1959 (Box-folder 3-22)
  - Convair-Astronautics Report: Preliminary Passenger Insertion Study: Project Mercury, April 24, 1959 (Box-folder 3-23)
  - Launching of a Manned Missile, June 3, 1959 (Box-folder 3-24)
  - Proposal: Inflight Abort-Control System, June 1959 (Box-folder 3-25)
  - Convair-Astronautics Report: Test Equipment Program for Abort Sensing and Implementation System for MA Flights, July 17, 1959 (Box-folder 3-26)
  - Project Mercury Mission Document: Mercury-Atlas Mission No.1, October 1, 1959 (Box-folder 3-27)
  - Talk to Society of Experimental Test Pilots: Mercury Program, October 9, 1959 (Box-folder 3-28)
  - Notes and Materials Related to Talk to Society of Experimental Test Pilots: Mercury Program, October 9, 1959 (Box-folder 3-29)
  - Project Mercury: Documentation/Communication Plans, November 2, 1959 (Box-folder 3-30)
  - Senate Report: Project Mercury Man-in-Space Program, December 1, 1959 (Box-folder 3-31)
  - Project Mercury Mission Document for Mercury-Redstone No.1, December 15, 1959 (Box-folder 3-32)
  - Liquid Oxygen Valve Installation, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 3-34)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 3-35)
- 1960
  - Review of Operational Plans for Mercury Orbital Mission, January 1960 (Box-folder 4-1)
  - Programs for Contractors' Briefing at WADC on Mercury Program, February 3, 1960 (Box-folder 4-2)
  - Program: project Mercury AeroMedical Flight Controller Briefing, May 23-27, 1960 (Box-folder 4-3)
  - NASA Technical Note D-253, May 1960 (Box-folder 4-4)
  - Project Mercury Discussion, June 20, 1960 (Box-folder 4-5)
  - Agenda: Briefing for Nigerian Visitors on Project Mercury, July 13, 1960 (Box-folder 4-6)
  - Post-Launch Report: Mercury-Atlas No. 1, August 2, 1960 (Box-folder 4-7)
  - Draft Memorandum: Abort Control Power Circuits, September 2, 1960 (Box-folder 4-8)
  - Project Mercury: Florida Test Procedure for MR-1, Section V, September 10, 1960 (Box-folder 4-9)
  - Project Mercury: Florida Test Procedure for MR-1, Section V, September 10, 1960 (Box-folder 4-10)
  - Project Mercury: Florida Test Procedure for MR-1, Section II, September 15, 1960 (Box-folder 4-11)
  - Convair-Astronautics Report: Flight Test Directive Mercury/Atlas Vehicle 77D, November 4, 1960 (Box-folder 4-12)
  - Project Mercury Flight Test Report: Mercury/ Atlas Mission No.1, November 4, 1960 (Box-folder 4-13)
  - Launch Procedure, Mercury MA-2, November 16, 1960 (Box-folder 4-14)
  - Post-Launch Report: Mercury-Redstone No. 1A, December 22, 1960 (Box-folder 4-15)
  - Project Mercury Flight Test Report: Little Joe Mission No.5, December 23, 1960 (Box-folder 4-16)
- 1961
  - NASA Technical Note D-532, January 1961 (Box-folder 4-17)
  - Post-Launch Report: Mercury-Redstone No.2, February 13, 1961 (Box-folder 4-19)
  - Project Mercury Operational Discussion, February 13, 1961 (Box-folder 4-20)
  - President's Ad Hoc Panel on Project Mercury March 1-5, 1961 (Box-folder 4-21)
  - Notes: Speech to Presidential Commission, March 3, 1961 (Box-folder 4-22)
  - Post-Launch Report: Mercury Atlas No. 2, March 13, 1961 (Box-folder 4-23)
  - Post-Launch report: Mercury-Little Joe No.5A, April 11, 1961 (Box-folder 4-24)
  - Memorandum Report for the Project Director, April 28, 1961 (Box-folder 4-25)
  - Flight Plan for the MR-3 Manned Flight: Paper Presented at Conference on Medical Results of the First U.S. Manned Suborbital Space Flight, June 6, 1961 (Box-folder 4-26)
  - Post-Launch Report: Mercury-Little Joe Mission 5B, June 12, 1961 (Box-folder 4-27)
  - Post-Launch Report: Mercury-Redstone No.3, June 16,1961 (Box-folder 4-28)
  - MR-4 Post Flight Debriefing of Virgil I. Grissom, July 21, 1961 (Box-folder 4-31)
  - Post Launch Memorandum Report: Mercury Redstonne No.4, August 6, 1961 (Box-folder 4-32)
  - MR-3 Post-Flight Debriefing of Alan B. Shepard, Jr., August 22, 1961 (Box-folder 4-33)
  - Post-Launch Report: Mercury-Redstone Mission 4, September 22, 1961 (Box-folder 4-34)
  - Post Launch Memorandum Report: Mercury-Atlas No.4, October 7, 1961 (Box-folder 4-35)
  - Post Launch Report: Mercury-Atlas Mission No.4, November 10, 1961 (Box-folder 4-36)
  - Post Launch Memorandum Report: Mercury-Atlas No.5, December 6, 1961 (Box-folder 4-37)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5-22)
- 1962
  - Mission Rules: Ma-6/13, June 1961- January 1962 (Box-folder 4-29)
  - Miscellaneous material: Ma-6/13, June 1961- January 1962 (Box-folder 4-30)
  - Post-Launch Memorandum for Mercury-Atlas No.6, March 5, 1962 (Box-folder 5-1)
  - Notes: Gemini Briefing, March 7,1962 (Box-folder 5-2)
  - Notes: Apollo Briefing, March 7, 1962 (Box-folder 5-3)
  - Project Mercury post-Launch Report: Mercury-Atlas Mission 5: Part 1 Mission Analysis, March 9, 1962 (Box-folder 5-4)
  - Project Mercury Post Launch Report: Mercury-Atlas Mission 5: Part II Data, March 9, 1962 (Box-folder 5-5)
  - MA-6 Communications: Text with Time Correlation, March 15, 1962 (Box-folder 5-6)
  - Mercury Operational Experience: Paper Presented at the Institute of Aerospace Sciences Conference, April 30-May 2, 1962 (Box-folder 5-7)
  - Flight Controller Handbook Spacecraft 18, April 26, 1962 (Box-folder 5-8)
  - Mercury Operational Experience: Paper Presented at the Institute of Aerospace Sciences Conference, April 30-May 2, 1962 (Box-folder 5-9)
  - MA-7/18: Mission Rules and Other Material, April-May 1962 (Box-folder 5-10)
  - Results of the Second United States Manned Orbital Space Flight, May 24, 1962 (Box-folder 5-11)
  - MA-6 Communications: Text with Time Correlation, March 15, 1962 (Box-folder 5-12)
  - MA-7: Report to Flight Director, Flight Plan, and Mission Briefing Agenda, etc., May-June 1962 (Box-folder 5-13)
  - Post-Launch Memorandum Report: Mercury-Atlas No.7, June 15, 1962 (Box-folder 5-14)
  - Second United States Manned Orbital Space Flight Conference, August 1962 (Box-folder 5-15)
  - Presentation to president John F. Kennedy on Mission Control Operations during Future Lunar Landings, September 10-12, 1962 (Box-folder 5-16)
  - MA-8/16: Mission Rules, Notes, and Memos, September-October 1962 (Box-folder 5-17)
  - Results of the Third United States Manned Orbital Space Flight, October 3, 1962 (Box-folder 5-18)
  - Post-Launch Memorandum Report for Mercury-Atlas No.8, October 23, 1962 (Box-folder 5-19)
  - Apollo Project: Memoranda and Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5-20)
  - Virginia tech: Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5-21)
- 1963
  - Briefing to Presidential Scientific Advisory Committee, March 3, 1963 (Box-folder 5-23)
  - NASA-USAF Gemini Briefing, March 14, 1963 (Box-folder 5-24)
  - Audio tape Segment on Re-entry (Retrofire/Gym)Enos, March 1963 (Box-folder 5-25)
  - Management Advisory Committee for Manned Space Flight, April 3, 1963 (Box-folder 6-1)
  - Mission Control for Manned Space Flight: Presentation to American Institute of Aeronautics Conference, Aprill 22-24, 1963 (Box-folder 6-2)
  - Proceedings: AIAA Second Manned Space Flight Meeting, April 22-44, 1963 (Box-folder 6-3)
  - Mercury Project Summary: results of the Fourth Manned Orbital Flight, May 15-16, 1963 (Box-folder 6-4)
  - A Review of the Knowledge Acquired from the First Manned Satellite Program: Presentation at the Virginia Tech Conference on Artificial Satelites, August 16, 1963 (Box-folder 6-5)
  - Conference on Artificial Satellites, August 16, 1963 (Box-folder 6-6)
  - Seminar on Engineering Design and Operation of manned Spacecraft: Mission Planning and Philosophy, August 1963 (Box-folder 6-7)
  - VPI Alumni Association Presentation, September 20, 1963 (Box-folder 6-8)
  - Briefing Materials Prepared for Dr. Robert G. Seamans and Dr. George E. Mueller, September 20-21, 1963 (Box-folder 6-9)
  - "What We Learned from Project Mercury": Article in Think Magazine, October-December, 1963 (Box-folder 6-10)
  - Post Launch memorandum Report: Apollo Pad Abort I, November 13, 1963 (Box-folder 6-11)
  - President's Scientific Advisory Commission Presentation, November 15, 1963 (Box-folder 6-12)
  - Apollo Contractor Executive Briefing, December 4, 1963 (Box-folder 6-13)
  - Review of Knowledge Acquired from the First manned Satellite Program: typescript, c. 1963 (Box-folder 6-14)
  - Arthur S. Flemming Award, District of Coumbia Jaycees, December 1963-March 1964 (Box-folder 6-15)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1963 (Box-folder 6-16)
  - Results of the Project Mercury Ballistic and Orbital chimpanzee Flights, 1963 (Box-folder 6-17)
- 1964
  - Review of Proposed Apollo Spacecraft Development Program: Memorandum, January 20, 1964 (Box-folder 6-18)
  - Presentation to 92nd Strategic Aerospace Wing, February 7, 1964 (Box-folder 6-19)
  - Apollo Flight Operations: Paper Presented to the American Astronautical Society Annual Meeting, May 4-7, 1964 (Box-folder 6-20)
  - VPI Alumni Association Presentation, May 18, 1964 (Box-folder 6-21)
  - Post-Launch Report for Apollo Mission A-001, May 28, 1964 (Box-folder 6-22)
  - Post-Launch report for Apollo Mission A-101, June 18, 1964 (Box-folder 6-23)
  - Presentations: Science and Technology Advisory Comittee for Manned Space Flight, June 30, 1964 (Box-folder 6-24)
  - Manned Spacecraft Center's Briefing and Tour for Dr. Seamans and Dr. Mueller, August 27, 1964 (Box-folder 6-25)
  - Mueller Presentation to Manned Spacecraft Center Senior Staff, October 5, 1964 (Box-folder 6-26)
  - AIAA/NASA Third Manned Space Flight Meeting, November 4-6, 1964 (Box-folder 6-27)
  - Materials for Speech at AIAA/NASA Third Manned Space Flight Meeting, November 4-6, 1964 (Box-folder 6-28)
  - GT-2 Gemini/Titan Mission Rules: 4th/5th Revision, December 25, 1964 (Box-folder 6-29)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1964 (Box-folder 6-30)
  - VPI Correspondence, 1964-65 (Box-folder 6-31)
  - Apollo Project Memoranda and Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 6-32)
- 1965
  - Post-Launch Report: Apollo Mission A-002, January 22, 1965 (Box-folder 7-1)
  - Post Launch report: Apollo Mission A-003, June 28, 1965 (Box-folder 7-2)
  - Post-Launch Report: Apollo Mission PA-2, July 29, 1965 (Box-folder 7-3)
  - Gemini Program Mission Report: Gemini IV, July 1965 (Box-folder 7-4)
  - Gemini V Technical Debriefing, U: Part I, September 1, 1965 (Box-folder 7-5)
  - Gemini Program Mission Report: Gemini VI-A, Octboer 1965 (Box-folder 7-6)
  - Manned Space Flight Experiments Symposium: Gemini missions III and IV, October 18-19, 1965 (Box-folder 7-7)
  - Gemini Program Mission report: Gemini V, October 1965 (Box-folder 7-8)